[music]
>> Hey, please subscribe. Thank you.
>> [music]
>> You know,
good morning. Something about Something
interesting about this internet,
interesting, fascinating, annoying, etc.
is that what it's doing
algorithmically
is it is constantly bringing
a bunch of people into a room
at different points in their timeline.
And so, what happens
is that
you will constantly
be
inter-
acting with people
at like their first time.
And because of its individual nature,
they think
that you should be meeting them at their
first time energy every time.
So, like I've got people that are just
now seeing that I did this interview
with Tasha K, who are like
seeing this for the first time.
They have their feelings about it. They
have their
their ire about it, etc., etc.
I did that interview
in December of last year.
And
>> [laughter]
>> my annoyance, my frustration, my damn, I
shouldn't have done that interview
happened in December of last year.
People are just seeing it now and want
me
to be meeting them at their first phase
of confusion or annoyance or disgust,
etc. And so, because I'm not,
they are
like, I don't know. Well, every week
they're kind of trying to come with some
new reason to discredit me. So, this
week the reason to discredit me is, "You
did an interview with Tasha K. You
should have known better. How dare you?"
So, that that that's this week's
discredit accreditation, okay?
The thing about it though is that I have
already addressed this.
And I am not
No one is able to keep meeting people.
You know what? Let's not even say able.
No one should
be expected
to keep meeting people
at their individual places in their
timeline.
It's not possible.
It's not practical.
You're in your timeline.
This internet
is inserting folks into your timeline on
their timeline. And the ego
is what forces people to think that you
owe them.
You owe them
I like
you you you owe them some sort of um
identifying of where they're where
they're stepping in. It's the same
reason why when I'm on live
and people come in and they announce,
"I'm here. What are we talking about it?
What are we talking about?" And I'm
always saying like, "Just join the
flow."
Just join the flow.
You know, the other thing is I need
y'all to really grasp that I will use
things like Tasha K or I will use big
headline items to talk about the root
items that we don't get to talk about.
That is that is a necessity because this
algorithm only feeds off the toxicity.
So, you splash the toxicity out there
and then you spray it down with the
truth.
And, you know, like someone here is
saying, "I think people expected more
from a person as educated you to kind of
do some research. Blah, blah, blah."
Blah, blah, blah.
The the the constant effort to try to
hold me to some false sense of
perfection as a counter to me holding
people to a very generic bottom line
sense of morality is not going to fly.
It's not It's not It's not It's not
going to fly.
>> [laughter]
>> It's not going to fly. Like, I There's a
very difference between making errors
and making choices.
There's a very big difference between
making errors and making choices,
right?
You know, people who are making a choice
even though they know the
That's very different. Very different.
You know, people are like, "How do you
not know about Tasha K?" Baby, that
woman is not in my She's not in my
orbit.
She's She's not in my orbit. The same
way that people think Amanda Seales
isn't doing anything. Well, I just
dropped a whole album.
And I'm doing interviews with folks all
over the world. But those folks are not
in their orbit, right? And so, that's
what social media does. It gives you
this like false sense that whatever
you're seeing is what everyone's seeing
and it's not.
You know?
It's not.
Um this woman the mushroom
he was supportive and then I saw him
under a post saying that he didn't like
my brand of autism
Because he says he feels that I speak
about autism from a autism supremacist
point of view. So he was blocked.
That's how that happened.
So
I just want to start you all today with
There you go, born to shine forever.
>> [laughter]
>> Get them together.
Get them together.
Um
No, I had already done the interview
when I did that live. So what are you
talking about? Kalachi, can you check
your
WhatsApp?
Kalachi don't be checking her WhatsApp,
y'all. Good morning, Kalachi.
>> [laughter]
>> I know y'all want to see another Kalachi
Amanda interview because she is
brilliant
[singing]
and I am brilliant.
Together we are brilliant.
[singing]
Together.
>> [laughter]
>> Um
So yeah, you're not going to get me
Here's the thing. You're not going to
get me to feel bad about myself.
And that's That's the thing. You know,
we don't do enough teaching and love. So
we are
constantly
doing the practice of teaching and shame
because so many folks just simply won't
learn without shame.
Okay?
They just won't learn without shame. We
We see that all the time. Like these
crackers, they don't learn without
shame.
They They they they don't.
Um
and
you know, even if I do go on, let's say
let let let's just say for for what it's
worth, let's just say I did know the
full extent of this Tasha K person. Um
I didn't go on her platform and and big
her up. Like I didn't go on her platform
and support her ideologies, etc., etc.
Like folks
Uh someone in here said folks go on a
poser's platforms to have discussions
all the time. Yes. However, I
I am expected
to do what everyone thinks I'm supposed
to do even though none of these people
have nothing to do with me.
So, you're never going to get me to feel
bad about myself. Shame is not an
effective tool for me.
>> [laughter]
>> And the other part of it is that um
I am not going to feel bad about myself
about about errors that I have made in
genuine error.
Like I'm just not.
I'm not I'm not doing that no more.
You know, so many of us are plagued our
whole lives with that.
You know, with like you can't make a
mistake, you know, then you
become a perfectionist, then you you
develop OCD. I mean, it just goes really
far.
And by the way, you're getting you're
getting this from people who don't hold
themselves to the same standard.
That's the other part. You're getting
that from people who don't hold
themselves to the same standard. Pass
that back to them, y'all.
Pass it back.
Create the standard upon which you want
to live.
Okay?
And oh, collect me, the likeability the
likeability conversation is so
disingenuous because none of them people
are likeable.
>> [laughter]
>> Like if you're having a conversation
about likeability, you're not likable.
That there's that.
And um
I am liked by the people I like. I like
Kolechi.
Kolechi like me.
Do you see how that work?
That's That's it.
That's it.
I like my man. He like me.
I like my friends. They like me.
I like Gary at the post office. He like
me. You see what I'm talking about?
You see what I'm talking about?
>> [laughter]
>> You don't even need You don't need
everyone to like you. It's not even
realistic and it's impractical and
honestly, it's very stressful, I would
imagine. I don't get invited to be in
people's weddings and I love that for
me.
I love that for me.
I love that I've never been a
bridesmaid. I love that for me.
You know who else like me?
Come here, Bubba.
He like me so much he want me to pet
him. Look. Look. Look. Look.
Yeah.
And And when people want you to care
that they don't like you, it's like I
can't.
I can't.
I've been really really working on
I only keep people in my life who can
correct me in love.
That's it. I only correct people I only
keep people in my life that can correct
me in can correct me in love. If you
have to correct me And like the other
day, I did not practice that and I got
checked.
And I had to check myself.
I had to check myself.
You feel me? Because it's not something
we're we're taught enough,
right? It's not a practice.
You know, Adrienne Marie Brown has a
book called Loving Corrections.
And it's not always effective, right?
Because you have so Thank you, Miller.
Because you have so many people who are
really deep deep deep,
right? In um
they're really deep deep deep in the
mire.
So, at the end of the day,
it's it's not always effective, but for
for many of us, so I'll tell you a
little story. Like when I was in
gymnastics, my coach used to yell crazy
at us, right? He used to yell crazy at
us. You know how gymnastics is. So, he
used to be yelling like, "God damn it!
Do it right! Blah blah blah blah blah
blah blah!" Okay?
And
um
I had to tell him as a 14-year-old,
"Hey, bro.
I don't work well with that.
You can keep that same volume. Instead,
however, can you use positive
reinforcement? Cuz that would really
work for me."
And he went from all that raw raw to
"COME ON, TIGER!"
EFFECTIVE.
You know, like me and my engineer, the
wonderful, beautiful, amazing Matt Cody,
who did my project who translator, we
were having a communication
issue.
You know? And And it was And it was like
one of those things where I'm like, "No,
like we we are very aligned. So, if
we're having a communication issue, like
I need to get to the bottom of that."
Right? And so,
I One night, I was like, "Okay, like I
just need to ask you some questions so I
can understand your communication
style." And let me just say this, too.
Questions really flood like they fluster
people. But for someone like me,
questions are not being done to like
undermine. They're being They're being
asked to undergird.
Do you understand the difference?
Some people are asking questions
disingenuously. They're They're trying
to
um
sort out some etc., etc. I am
asking questions to create a foundation
upon which we can build. I'm asking
questions so that we can get to like a
a shared um
uh
so we can get to like a an agreement
space, right? So, we can get to common
ground. That's what I'm That's why I'm
asking questions. And so, because we
live in such a disingenuous society that
is built on narcissism, the concept of
asking questions can be very, very
offensive to people.
Right? But for someone who's like
neurodivergent like me, like questions
are like the the the very
um
fabric of my existence.
Okay? I'm asking myself questions all
day long. Should you have said that that
way? What do you think about that?
What's a better way to do that? How What
is that? Why did they do that that way?
Right?
I love when people ask me questions. And
it's so interesting to see how
when um
when people are not used to being able
to ask questions, they also don't even
know how to ask you questions.
Right? Because they're so used to being
to questions being seen as a
um a negative.
So, like even even with my partner, like
like encouraging him
to like ask me questions, I don't get
offended by that. I like it.
>> [laughter]
>> I like it. It helps me understand me. It
helps you understand me.
Right? So,
um
with the questions thing,
it's it's Yeah, my metacognition is off
the charts. I'll be metacognitioning all
day long. So, with the questions thing,
it's like I'm always
trying to understand. And so, me and
Matt, I literally was so happy that he
just let me ask him some questions about
how he receives information.
So, that I could show up better in
communication.
Right?
So, like some of the questions I asked
him were like, "Okay,
are you what when I say a
Thank you, MF Greyland. When I say a
sentence, what when I when I give you a
um a
uh response of notes, right?
Um I will, Neon Rosebud. When I give you
a response about notes,
do you find yourself
um responding more to the detail, or do
you find yourself responding more to the
overarching message?
Do you find yourself
being attracted to the negative?
I like on a scale of 1 to 10, how
attracted are you to the negative versus
the positive? Like these are the types
of questions I was asking him to help me
learn how to communicate to him better.
And when I'm telling you, after
we didn't have the same problems.
I will do that, Kufiya. Awesome.
We didn't have the same problems after
that because I was able to take that
assessment and apply it differently. So,
it allowed me to
change how I was communicating with him.
So, now it was like instead of just
giving him the overall when I'm giving
him my notes, I know that I need to be
very very very detailed and I need to do
it um
like separately, right? It let me know
that like I need to start with a very
genuine Not genuine, that's not the word
I'm looking for. It is genuine, but I
need to start with a very general
positive.
Right?
Um I need to
and I need to not list. I need to confer
about each item separately.
Because if I give him all of them all at
once, it they all flood together and
then it creates confusion.
And so, this was like super duper useful
and it was only able to happen because
he was generous enough to engage in the
back and forth without feeling like he
was being probed.
You know? And he was like
And after he was like, "You know, thank
you. Like I've never had anyone
like take the time to like try to
understand my communication style."
Um
And I be honest, it was the first time
that I had ever done it in such a
deliberate way. I think we I think we do
that over time kind of naturally
sometimes, but this was like I'm going
to make a deliberate point to do this
and it just made the difference.
Really. So,
um I say all of that to say that, you
know, I'm in a constant practice of
trying to be, um,
my most effective human self in this
experience.
And I consider effectiveness
attached to growth.
No, not my man, my producer.
I consider effectiveness, not my
producer, sorry, my engineer, attached
to growth. How
how much opportunity
for growth
and
life
am I creating space for?
And that is what I consider the measure
of my efficacy as a human.
That's what's up, Kiki.
So, I hope you all have a good day.
I hope this gave you all some insights.
And,
um,
and,
uh,
smell the flowers.
>> [music]